const questions = [
  {

  },
  {
   
  question: "what is true avout land breeze", 
  answer1: "only at noon", 
  answer2: "only at day", 
  answer3: "Blows from land towards sea at night",
  answer4: "Blows from sea towards land at afternoon",
  correctAnswer: 3
  },
  {

question: "Which of the following surfaces is likely to produce a higher than average diurnal variation of temp?",
answer1: "rock of concrete",
answer2: "water", 
answer3: "snow", 
answer4: "vegitation",
correctAnswer: 1

  },
  {
  question: "Flying at FL 180 in the NH where the wind is geostrophic, the true altitude remains constant. what is true for the wind?", 
  answer1: "There is a crosswind from the left", 
  answer2: "there is a crosswind from the right", 
  answer3: "there is no crosswind",
  answer4: "without knowing the temperature at FL 180, this question can not be answered", 
  correctAnswer: 3

  },
  {
question: "You are flying at FL 250, heading 090. The wind is comming from your left. Which of the following is correct?", 
answer1: "you are flying towards an are of high pressure",
answer2: "you have an area of cold air to the right",
answer3: "You have cold air behind you",
answer4: "you are flying towards an area of low pressure", 
correctAnswer: 4

  },
  {
question: "You are flying in the 500hPa pressure surface in the direction of 270 dgr. In the NH. Which of the following statements is correct whe we assume that the wind is geostrophic?",
answer1: "in in this pressure the wind comes from the direction 180 degrees", 
answer2: "in in this pressure the wind comes from the direction  360 degrees", 
answer3: "in in this pressure the wind comes from the direction  090 degrees",
answer4: "in in this pressure the wind comes from the direction 270 degrees",
correctAnswer: 2
  },
  {
question: "In the NH the speed of the thermal wind in the layer between 5000 ft and 14000ft is given as 60kts and low temp lies to the NE. The geostrophic wind at 5000 is 200/35. which of the following is most likely wind at 14000 ft", 
answer1: "235/70",
answer2: "280/70",    
answer3: "330/25", 
answer4: "305/35", 
correctAnswer: 2
  },
  {
question: "An aircraft departrs from A, elevation 1200', With QNH 980 hPa set. The altimeter is not reset. When landing at B, elevation 2500', where the QNH 1005, the altimeter will read.",
answer1: "1950",
answer2: "3175", 
answer3: "550", 
answer4: "1825",  
correctAnswer: 4

  },
  {
question: "Which of the following describes a warm occlusion?",
answer1: "the air mass ahead of the front is drier than the air mass behind the front", 
answer2: "the warmer air mass is ahead of the original warm front", 
answer3: "the coldest air mass is ahead of the original warm front", 
answer4: "the air mass behind the front is more unstable than the air mass ahead of the front", 
correctAnswer: 3 


  },
  {
  
question: "The altimeter subscale is set to 1030 hPa and the altimeter reads 3500'. QNH is 994 hPa. what is the altitude of the aircraft?",
answer1: "2990",
answer2: "4472",
answer3: "3500",
answer4: "2528",   
correctAnswer: 4
  },
  {

question: "Take off from an airport with QNH 1020 hPa. When passing through the transition altitude you are resetting your altimeter to the standard. What happens with the altimeter reading?", 
answer1: "increase",
answer2: "apparently nothing", 
answer3: "decrease",
answer4: "it showsks 5000",
correctAnswer: 3
  },
  {

question: "An aircraft is flying at FL60 indicated towards a mountain range with an elevation of 3900'. if during the flight the QNH in the mountain area falls to 989 hPa and the altimeter sub scale is not reset, what will the terrain clearence be over the mountain range?", 
answer1: "2748",
answer2: "2100",
answer3: "2568",
answer4: "1452",
correctAnswer: 4
  },
  {

question: "The temperature and dewpoint are within 1 degree of each other. what is most likely during the following night?",
answer1: "Fog and low St",
answer2: "Clear and cold",
answer3: "Ts",
answer4: "good visibillity", 
correctAnswer: 1
  },
  {
question: "Througout the 24 hrs of a day the relativ humidity can be expected to:",
answer1: "increase during the day and decrease at night",
answer2: "stay reasonably constant througout the 24hrs",
answer3: "Reduce during the day and increase at night",
answer4: "only change with a change of airmass",
correctAnswer: 3
  },
  {
question: "From summer to winter, the movement of the jetstreams over the north atlantic and their speed change, will be:",
answer1: "N and increase",
answer2: "N and decrease",
answer3: "S and increase",	
answer4: "S and decrease",
correctAnswer: 3
  },
  {
question: "Radiation fog is most likely to be formed:",
answer1: "During the day in tropical areas",
answer2: "after a cold and gusty night",
answer3: "over land during a clear night with calm winds",
answer4: "over sea after a clear night with calm winds.",
correctAnswer: 3
  },
  {

question: "NH. Eastarly jet - when and where does it exist?",
answer1: "summer, southern asia",
answer2: "winter, southern europe",
answer3: "summer, southern europe",
answer4: "winter, nothern canada",
correctAnswer: 1
  },
  {
question: "Where is the coldest part of cold occlusion?,
answer1: "just at the point of the occlusion",
answer2: "before the front",
answer3: "behind the front",
answer4: "under warm airmass",
correctAnswer: 3

  },
  {

question: "Where does the tropical maritime air originate?",
answer1: "North Africa",
answer2: "The inlands of Siberia",
answer3: "Azorean Islands in the Atlantic Ocean",		
answer4: "Greenland",
correctAnswer: 3
  },
  {
question: "What type of front/ occlusion usually moves the fastest?",
answer1: "warm occlusion",
answer2: "cold front",
answer3: "warm front",
answer4: "cold occlusion", 
correctAnswer: 2
  },
  {
question:"What conditions will cause the lowest surface temperature during night?",
answer1: "clear skies, calm winds", 
answer2: "cloudy skies, strong wind",
answer3: "clear skies, strong wind",
answer4: "cloudy skies, calm wind.",
correctAnswer: 1
  },
  {




































   
   
   
   
   
   
   
   
  }
];
